<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Adar Kahiri</title>
    <link>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Adar Kahiri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 13:42:31 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://adarkahiri.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hash Functions For The Technical Layman</title>
      <link>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/hash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 14:43:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/hash/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I became interested in cryptographic hash functions. To my surprise, I couldn&#39;t find any good, comprehensive resources online explaining exactly how they work, and so I had to look through dozens of articles, textbooks, and papers to get just a fraction of the level of understanding I wanted. I figured I&#39;d write this post to save others interested in hash functions the trouble of doing what I did.
In terms of prerequisites, besides basic programming knowledge, you should know what bit-wise operators are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Platitudes</title>
      <link>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/platitudes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 22:37:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/platitudes/</guid>
      <description>Platitudes get a bad rap, often seen as being of little substance. But I think some of these ostensibly trite statements contain time-tested knowledge that is currently under-appreciated in our world, judging by how many people actually seem to live by them. Here are some of my favourite.
 Two wrongs don&amp;rsquo;t make a right. Treat others the way you want to be treated. What goes around comes around. The road to hell is paved with good intentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof of the Fundamental Theorem of Algebra</title>
      <link>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/fundamental-theorem-of-algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 15:05:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/fundamental-theorem-of-algebra/</guid>
      <description>About a week ago, I read a rather elegant proof of the fundamental theorem of algebra involving the fundamental group of a circle. It&#39;s among the more surprising proofs I&#39;ve read. As someone who knows very little about algebra and topology, I&#39;m accustomed to algebraic structures being used to solve topological problems, but this proof bridged the two worlds in exactly the opposite way.
When I first read the proof, I was a little confused, mainly because I didn&#39;t understand the motivation behind the methods used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Axioms</title>
      <link>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/personal-axioms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 20:44:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/personal-axioms/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I can remember, I&amp;rsquo;ve questioned the orthodoxy around me. It started with questioning the existence of a God, which my family assured me was real, and has progressed to questioning all sorts of opinions, ideologies, and beliefs.
While I have a few deeply held convictions, most of my opinions are loosely-held, and often I have a hard time forming opinions which I consider a truly fair conclusion to a rigorous analysis of the issues at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change of Variables and the Jacobian</title>
      <link>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/jacobian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:55:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adarkahiri.com/blog/jacobian/</guid>
      <description>In single-variable calculus, we can integrate functions of the form
\[g&#39;(x)f(g(x))\]
by &#39;rephrasing&#39; the entire integral as an integral of \(g(x)\) instead of an integral of \(x\). This is known as substitution. For example, consider the following integral:
\[\int x e^{x^2} dx\]
Integrating this function as it currently is is painfully annoying, and so Leibniz, one of the fathers of calculus, came up with a way to simplify this integral. The first step in doing so is to notice that</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
